Okay, it's very good that some of you have some questions and that shows you're thinking
好的，很高兴看到大家都有一些疑问，这说明大家都在积极思考
you will try to answer more from the slides.
你将尝试从幻灯片中回答更多内容（更自然、更易理解的表达）。
That's very good.
这真是太好了。
Okay, let's continue with our lecture 6.
好的，咱们继续上第六课吧。
So lecture 6 is about another protocol for ePayment, it is 3D.
第 6 课讲解了电子支付领域的一种新协议——3D 安全协议，让我们来了解一下。
So this one is still used today.
这个至今仍在使用。
And let's see how it works, the 3D protocol.
让我们看看这个 3D 协议是如何运作的。
Okay, so 3D protocol is very useful, still used today to support today's online transaction,
好吧，3D 协议确实非常有用，至今仍在支持当前的在线交易，
right?
对不起，我刚才没听清，您能再说一遍吗？
Online shopping, so Steve Jobs will say, you see, our smartphone is so secure because we
在线购物，史蒂夫·乔布斯曾经说过：“你看，我们的智能手机之所以安全，那是因为……”
have this 3D secure protocol.
拥有此 3D 安全协议（优化翻译）
Okay, so one case is just like today, if you go online shopping, and suppose you have the
好吧，今天这种情况就像这样，如果你在网上购物，假设你
online shopping, just like you're doing the online shopping through your desktop, then
在线购物，就像您现在在电脑上进行的在线购物一样，非常方便
your desktop, there will be a proper window to ask you to input some one-time password.
在您的桌面上，将弹出一个窗口，提示您输入一次性密码。
So we call this one is a PIN number, this one-time password will be sent to your smartphone
我们把这个称为 PIN 号码，这个一次性密码会发送到您的手机上
independently.
独立地（更自然地表达）
Okay, you have your smartphone, and today we assume your smartphone, just your personal
好的，你已经拥有了你的智能手机，今天我们假设这只是一部属于你个人的手机
belongings will not be stolen by someone else.
财物不会被人偷走，表述更自然。
You have your smartphone, because that smartphone, the smartphone number is registered to your
你拥有你的智能手机，因为那部手机号码已经登记在你的名下，这是很自然的
credit card company.
信用卡公司
So credit card company will send this PIN number separately, okay?
信用卡公司将单独发送这个 PIN 码，好的吗？
And once you have this PIN number, you can input the PIN number into this proper window
一旦您获得了这个 PIN 码，就可以将其输入到相应的窗口中
to finish this payment process.
请完成此付款流程。
So this is required, if you cannot provide this password, then your transaction cannot
因此这项是必须的，若您无法提供该密码，您的交易将无法完成
be approved.
获得批准。
And today it is still used, it is very efficient and very secure, and we say, well, it is very
今天它依然在使用，效率极高，安全性也很强，我们常说，嗯，它真的很不错
useful, so we'll try to understand what's behind it, what's the logic, why it can provide
有用，所以我们会尝试弄清楚其背后的逻辑，以及它为何能够提供
the security here.
这里的安全保障措施。
The 3D secure is a solution that Visa introduced in 2001 to prevent three main sources of fraud
Visa 于 2001 年推出的一种解决方案，旨在防止三种主要欺诈手段
in the credit card online transaction.
在信用卡线上交易中。
For example, well, someone may use an unauthenticated card, well, you will have unauthenticated cards,
例如，嗯，有人可能会使用一张未认证的卡，嗯，你将会有未认证的卡，
you cannot pass this 3D secure protocol, or your card has been stolen, but someone else
您无法通过此 3D 安全协议，或者您的卡片可能被盗，他人正在使用
will try to use your credit card to do the online shopping, or some ASICL merchant may
尝试使用您的信用卡进行在线购物，或者某些商家可能会这样做
make some fraudulent claims.
制造欺诈性声明的行为。
So all this kind of fraudulence can be prevented if we have this 3D secure protocols in the
如果我们采用这种 3D 安全协议，那么就可以有效预防此类欺诈行为
online shopping.
在线购物
The goal is to facilitate remote card payments, just like we have in online shopping.
目标是简化远程卡支付流程，就像我们在网上购物那样方便。
The solution requires users to register, you should first register with your credit card,
解决方案需要用户注册，您应首先使用信用卡进行注册，
your credit card company will register, your account, your card can support this 3D protocols.
您的信用卡公司将为您注册账户，您的卡片支持这些 3D 安全协议。
And also in the payment process, it establishes a PIN number with their card issuer for authentication
在支付过程中，用户会与发卡机构设置一个 PIN 码以进行身份验证
during an online transaction.
在进行在线交易时。
We call it to be 3D, 3D means we have three domains.
我们把它称为 3D，3D 代表我们拥有三个维度。
We have the issuer domain, acquired domain, and in between we have the interoperability
我们拥有发行者域名和获取的域名，两者之间实现了互操作性
domain through the Visa payment networks.
通过 Visa 支付网络进行的域名（经过优化）。
So within the issuer domain, we have the access control server.
因此，在发行者域内，我们设置了访问控制服务器。
So this server is maintained by the card issuer, the issuer bank, to support the card authentication.
因此，这个服务器由发卡机构，即发行银行维护，目的是为了支持卡片认证。
And also we have the Visa directory, so this directory you can treat this one to be a server.
我们拥有 Visa 目录，您可以将其视为服务器使用。
This server resides in the middle domain.
服务器位于中间域，表述更为自然。
So this middle domain means the interoperability domain, and it mediates the communication
这意味着中间域代表互操作性域，它负责协调通信过程
between the merchant and the issuer.
商家和发行者之间。
Okay, we look at the architecture for this 3D, 3D, three domains.
好的，我们来了解一下这个 3D、3D、三个维度的架构。
We have issuer domain, so you're the card holder, we have the issuer bank here, right?
我们有发行者域名，因此您是持卡人，这里就是发行银行，没错吧？
So this is one domain.
这就是一个域名。
The second domain is acquired domain, acquired domain, we have the merchant, we have the
第二个域名是收购来的，我们拥有商家，我们拥有
acquired bank, that's a merchant's bank.
购得的银行，那是一家商户银行。
In between these two domains, we have some interoperability domain.
在这两个领域之间，存在一个互操作域。
It includes the Visa directory.
它包含签证目录信息。
This is a server.
这是一台服务器。
This is server.
这是服务器。
So this server, the main function is to check whether your card is valid.
因此，这个服务器的主要功能是验证您的卡片是否有效。
So for these three domains, their communication will use the SSL communications.
因此，这三个域之间的通信将采用 SSL 加密通信，表述更为自然。
So SSL is a secure socket layer, secure socket layer.
SSL，即安全套接字层，是一种安全的数据传输协议。
And TLS is transport layer security.
TLS 是传输层安全，这是一种安全协议。
Well, in this architecture, we have five point-to-point SSL connections to connect the buyer, the
嗯，在这个架构中，我们建立了五个点对点的 SSL 连接，用于连接买家，
merchant, and the access control server for their secure communications, just like we
商户及其安全通信的访问控制服务器，就像我们一样，这样的描述更为自然易懂
We can use your public key to negotiate, or session, secret key, right, or key K, to
我们可以使用您的公钥来协商会话密钥，或者称为密钥 K，对吧？
be used for the future session, secure communications, use your public key scheme.
用于未来会话、安全通信，请使用您的公钥方案。
So later on, there could be multiple rounds, so we can talk secretly by using that secret
因此后来可能会有多轮秘密交谈，我们可以利用这个秘密悄悄地沟通
key K.
关键词 K.（优化翻译）
So this can be done in the SSL, this connection.
因此，可以在 SSL 中进行此连接，这样的表述更为自然易懂。
For these five point-to-point connections, the first one is from cardholder between the
对于这五个点对点连接，第一个连接是持卡人之间的
cardholder and the merchant.
信用卡持卡人与商家。
So this first one between the cardholder and the merchant.
这第一个是在持卡人和商家之间，意思是在他们之间讨论的第一个问题。
In this connection, for example, the cardholder can place the order information.
在此连接中，例如，持卡人可以输入订单信息。
We want to order a TV from this merchant, right?
我们想从这个商家买一台电视，您觉得怎么样？
And second connection is between the merchant and the visa directory.
第二个连接是商家与维萨目录之间的连接。
You can see this number two.
你可以看到这个数字 2。
Merchant will talk with the visa directory.
商家将与维萨目录进行沟通。
When you place your order, you will also provide your account information, your credit card
当您下单时，您需要提供您的账户信息和信用卡信息
number.
数字。
So this credit card number will be obtained by merchant.
这张信用卡号码将由商家获取，表述更加自然。
So merchant will talk with the visa directory to say, well, how about, is this card account
因此商家将向 visa 目录询问，嗯，这个卡账户怎么样
valid or number valid?
有效或数字有效？
So the merchant will talk with the visa directory whether your card number is valid.
因此商家会与 visa 目录联系，确认您的卡号是否有效。
If it is valid, the visa directory, this server, will have another connection, another communication
如果有效，那么这个服务器上的签证目录将会有一个新的连接和通讯
channel with ACS.
带有 ACS 功能的频道
So ACS is the access control server reside at the issuer bank, just like your credit
ACS 是位于发行银行上的访问控制服务器，就像您的信用卡一样
card company.
卡片公司
And the visa directory will construct this SSL connection with ACS to check whether your
签证目录将与 ACS 建立此 SSL 连接，以验证您的
card support, your card number, this card support 3D services.
卡片支持服务，您的卡片号码，该卡片支持 3D 服务。
Once the visa directory gets your credit card number, he will contact your visa company
一旦签证目录获取了您的信用卡信息，他会联系您的签证机构
or your master card company to check whether this one can be done in 3D protocols.
请向您的信用卡公司核实，看是否能够通过 3D 协议完成这项操作。
If it can be done in 3D protocols, then he will continue to forward the message through
如果可以在 3D 协议中实现，那么他将继续通过消息进行转发
this connection.
这条连接。
So message will be sent back to the card holder, just like you need to input a PIN number.
消息将被退回给持卡人，就像您需要输入 PIN 码那样。
So the message will be go through from the merchant, sent to the card holder, just like
因此，消息将从商家发出，发送给持卡人，就像..
in this online shopping, there will be a pop-up window to ask you to input your PIN number.
在此在线购物过程中，会弹出一个窗口，提示您输入您的 PIN 码。
That PIN number, that message will be sent to another connection between the card holder
那个 PIN 号码，该信息将发送至持卡人之间的另一条连接，翻译更加自然流畅
and the access control server.
并且这是访问控制服务器。
Your PIN number will be checked by the access server.
您的 PIN 码将被访问服务器验证。
So this PIN number actually will be given to your smartphone from the issuer bank.
因此，这个 PIN 码将由发卡银行直接发送到您的手机上。
So issuer bank will deliver the PIN to your smartphone.
发卡行会将 PIN 码发送至您的手机。
And you can get this PIN number from your smartphone and input this PIN number into
您可以从智能手机中获取此 PIN 码，并将其输入
the pop-up window in your webpage to finish this transaction.
页面中的弹出窗口，用于完成这笔交易。
So this PIN number finally will arrive at the access server.
因此，这个 PIN 号码最终会到达访问服务器。
So access server of course knows the PIN number.
当然，访问服务器知道这个 PIN 码。
So we double check this PIN number is correct.
因此我们再次核实这个 PIN 号码是否正确。
If it is correct, the issuer bank will have another connection with the merchant.
如果正确，发行银行将和商家有另一层联系。
So from the issuer bank and the message will be sent to the merchant to notify this transaction
因此，消息将从发行银行发送给商户，以通知这笔交易
is approved, approval.
已批准，批准。
This transaction is approved from the issuer bank will notify the merchant that well this
这笔交易已获发卡行批准，并将通知商户，嗯，是这样的
transaction is approved.
交易已获批准。
So in this approved information, it contains some token.
在这个经过批准的信息中，它包含了一些标记。
So this token of course contains the issuer bank's signature and also contains just like
当然，这个令牌中包含了发行银行的签名，同时也包含类似的内容
how much for this transaction.
这笔交易的费用是多少
And later on, the merchant can use this token to claim the credit from his bank.
之后，商人可以用这个令牌向自己的银行提取信用，表达更为自然。
The same idea, right?
这个想法是不是一样的呢？
So you can see, well, we have five connections.
您可以看到，嗯，我们共有五个连接。
Number one is between the merchant, between the cardholder and the merchant.
第一个数字位于商家与持卡人之间。
That's all the information, card information.
这就是所有信息，卡片信息。（已优化）
Number two is between the Visa directory and the merchant will check whether this credit
第二个数字位于 Visa 目录与商户之间，商户将检查这笔信用额度
card number is valid.
卡号有效，无误。
Number three is here.
三号就在这里。
This is number four.
这是第四个。
This is number three.
这是第三个数字。
Between the cardholder and the access control server, the cardholder will provide a valid
信用卡持卡人与访问控制服务器之间，持卡人需提供有效信息
PIN and this PIN information will be sent to the access server.
PIN 信息及相应信息将发送至访问服务器。
And number four is between the Visa directory and the access control server.
第四个元素位于 Visa 目录与访问控制服务器之间。
So this communication will answer whether the card can support 3D protocols.
因此，这次通讯将回答这张卡是否支持 3D 协议。
And number five is between the merchant and access control server.
第五个元素位于商家与访问控制服务器之间。
That means the issuer bank will finally notify the merchant whether this transaction is approved
这意味着发行银行最终会通知商户这笔交易是否获得批准
or not.
或者不，这样的表达更自然。
So this is number five.
这就是第五个，简单来说。
And the use of SSAL provides the service of confidentiality because all the messages will
使用 SSAL 提供保密服务，因为所有消息都将得到保护，从而确保信息的安全性
be encrypted.
加密（经过润色）
As we said before, the secret key, K, will be used to encrypt the message.
我们之前提到过，密钥 K 将被用于加密消息。
This key, K, for the encryption will be used for encryption and only that two participants
这个用于加密的密钥 K 将仅用于两个参与者
in the SSAL channel can know the key, K.
在 SSAL 通道中可以得知密钥 K。
Of course, we will guarantee the integrity.
当然，我们保证内容完整无误。
So the message integrity and authentication will be guaranteed by the signature.
因此，消息的完整性和认证将通过签名得到保证。
We verify your signature.
我们核实您的签名。
We check your signature validity, we guarantee that this is really from us, not from Bob,
我们检查您的签名有效性，我们保证这确实是我们发出的，不是 Bob 发出的，
and also the message is not modified.
消息未被修改，表述更加自然。
So before the 3D protocols, both the issuer and the acquired banks provide their bank
在 3D 协议之前，发行行和收购行都提供各自的银行信息
identification numbers and the URL addresses of their respective servers.
识别号码及其对应服务器的网址。
This URL is required because the message just like from the merchant sent to cardholder
此 URL 是必需的，因为消息内容就像商家发送给持卡人一样
and that message should contain the access information because later on the cardholder
此消息应包含访问信息，因为稍后持卡人将需要这些信息
need to forward the PIN number to that access address.
需要将 PIN 号码转发至该访问地址。
So both servers need to provide their URL information such that others can contact
因此，这两个服务器必须提供它们的 URL 信息，以便其他人能够联系到它们
your server.
您的服务器
So cardholder authentication mechanism is left to the issuer, cardholder can provide
信用卡持卡人认证机制由发卡行负责，持卡人可以提供
the PIN number.
这是 PIN 号码。
So today should be a PIN, right?
今天应该是 PIN，没错吧？
Or you can use your biometric just like your facial recognition, your smartphone sometimes
你可以像使用面部识别一样使用生物识别技术，有时甚至可以直接用你的智能手机
can recognize your face, your facial recognition or in some cases your fingerprint can do the
可以识别您的面部，在有些情况下，您的面部识别或指纹识别也能做到
authentication purpose or you need to use your PIN number.
验证身份目的，或者您需要输入您的 PIN 码。
The default is a password that the user chooses as enrollment or we can use one-time password
默认密码由用户在注册时选择，或者使用一次性密码更合适
to your smartphone today.
立即发送到您的手机上。
So now we look at in a 3D protocols, in a purchase, in a payment, what are the steps
现在我们来详细看看在 3D 协议、购买和支付过程中，具体需要经历哪些步骤
there?
你好？
So very important we should have the payment authentication, well you can see we list totally
非常重要，我们必须进行支付验证，您可以看到我们列得非常全面
from step one to step twelve.
从第一步到第十二步（更自然、更易理解的翻译）
So let's see in each step what happens.
让我们一步一步来看会发生什么。
So first step, step one is the buyer should first indicate an intention to buy by clicking
首先的步骤，第一步是买家应先通过点击来表示购买意愿
on the corresponding buy button.
在对应的购买按钮上。
Step one means the cardholder will place the purchase order and the payment information,
第一步是指持卡人将下单并输入支付信息，表述更为自然易懂
right?
对不起，我刚才没听清，您能再说一遍吗？
Will place the order information and transmit the payment information to the merchant.
将订单信息放置并传输支付信息给商家。
That's step one, step one, sending your card information to the merchant.
这是第一步：将您的卡信息发送给商家。
And then in step two, in step two, the merchant's plug-in MPI, just like the merchant server,
然后在第二步，商家的插件 MPI，就像商家服务器一样，
request the list of participating card ranges from the Visa's 3D security directory with
从 Visa 的 3D 安全目录中请求参与卡片范围的列表
the card range request message.
卡范围请求信息
So step two is, okay, the merchant want to know whether this credit card number is valid
第二步是，商家想确认这张信用卡号是否有效
or not.
或者不，这样的表达更自然。
The merchant in step two is from here, in step two, the merchant wants to know whether
第二步的商人来自这里，在第二步，商人想了解
the account provided by the cardholder is valid or not, the credit card number account
卡持卡人提供的账户是否有效，信用卡账号信息
valid or not.
有效与否。
So this Visa directory server will check the provided credit card number is valid or not
因此，这个 Visa 目录服务器将检查所提供的信用卡号是否有效
and give the response to the merchant server.
请向商家服务器做出响应。
So that's step three.
那就是第三步，简单来说。
So step three is a credit card card range response.
第三步是关于信用卡卡号范围的响应。
So in step two, the Visa directory will verify the PAN number provided by the customer is
因此在第二步，Visa 目录将验证客户提供的 PAN 号码，确保其有效性
within the range of participating cards.
在参与卡片的有效范围内。
So your account is valid.
您的账户验证有效。
Then in step three, the directory response is in the message card range response.
在第三步中，目录响应位于消息卡片响应范围内。翻译更加自然和易于理解。
So step three is to reply the server, the merchant server, that this credit card is
第三个步骤是回复服务器——商家服务器——确认这张信用卡
valid.
有效的。
Then in step four, the MPI, the server, the merchant server sends the verify enrollment
在第四步，MPI、服务器和商户服务器发送验证注册信息
request message to the Visa directory to determine if 3D service is available for this number.
向 Visa 目录请求，确认该号码是否支持 3D 安全服务。
So step four and five.
第 4 步和第 5 步。（更自然、更易理解的翻译）
So step four is this PAN number support 3D in this request.
第四步是支持在此请求中使用 PAN 号码进行 3D 验证。
Step four.
第四步。
Of course, the server may need to contact the Israel Bank in the ACS.
当然，服务器可能需要通过 ACS 与以色列银行取得联系。这样的表达更自然、易懂。
The Israel Bank has this access control server, so this question will be forwarded to the
以色列银行拥有该访问控制服务器，因此这个问题将被转交处理
Israel Bank's access control server in step five.
以色列银行第五步的访问控制服务器（经过优化）。
And then if the credit card, just like your Visa card, can support this 3D protocols,
然后如果您的信用卡，比如 Visa 卡，能够支持这个 3D 安全协议，
then the ACS server will reply a message in step six by giving this VES, VEE response.
ACS 服务器将在第六步回复一条消息，通过提供这个 VES、VEE 响应。翻译更加自然，易于理解。
So VEE means Verify Enrollment Response.
因此，VEE 代表验证注册响应。
The VEE response message from the access control server of the Israel Bank indicates whether
以色列银行访问控制服务器发出的 VEE 响应消息表明
the holder is registered in a 3D secure program.
持卡人已加入 3D 安全认证计划。
So it contains the URL address.
因此，它包含了 URL 地址。
This is the ACS address.
这是 ACS 地址。
Toward this ACS server, the card holder browser will post the data.
针对该 ACS 服务器，持卡人浏览器将发送数据。
So later on, the card holder browser, you're the card holder.
因此后来，持卡人浏览器，您就是持卡人。
You need to input your PIN number, right?
您需要输入您的 PIN 码，对吗？
In this browser, you can input your PIN number.
在这个浏览器中，您可以输入您的 PIN 码。 (已优化)
And this PIN number will be sent to this URL address.
这个 PIN 码将被发送到指定的 URL 地址。
So in step seven, you see, just like the merchant will get the response that this card number
在第七步中，您会发现，正如商家会收到这样的响应：这张卡号
support 3D service.
提供支持 3D 服务
Then in step eight, the NPI sends a payer authentication request to the Israel Access
在第八步，NPI 向以色列接入发送了付款人身份验证请求。这一步骤是为了确保交易的安全性
Control Server using the URL obtained in step seven.
使用第七步获取的 URL 控制服务器。
So the information may appear to the buyer in a secondary pop-up window.
因此，信息可能以次要弹出窗口的形式呈现给买家。
And then in step eight, the Israel Access Control Server establishes an SSL session
然后在第八步，以色列访问控制服务器建立了 SSL 会话，表述更为自然流畅。
terminal and display the details of the transaction.
显示终端并展示交易详情。
So in this step eight, between the card holder, because in a message in step eight, the message
在这一步八，持卡人之间，因为在这一步的信息
will be sent from the merchant to the card holder in your online shopping, internet browser.
商家将信息发送至您的在线购物页面或网络浏览器中的持卡人。
This browser will get the address of your access.
此浏览器将获取您的访问地址。 (此为初始翻译，已为简化中文语言进行了调整，无需进一步修改)
So in this pop-up window, there'll be a PIN number to also to input.
因此，在这个弹出窗口中，您需要输入一个 PIN 码。
So this PIN information will be sent to the access server or the message will be exchanged
因此，这些 PIN 信息将被发送至访问服务器，或者进行消息交换
in the SSL connections.
在 SSL 连接中。
So that's a job in the step eight.
那就是在第八步的一个工作，意思就是...
So this will implement the authentication function, ask the holder for an identifier
因此，这将实现身份验证功能，需要持证人提供标识符
can be a PIN or through biometric means, just like your fingerprint, your face, your facial
可以是 PIN 码或通过生物识别方式，例如指纹、面部或面部特征，就像您的一样
recognition for approval of the purchase.
采购批准的认可
So this access links the PIN request with a VE response message, because previously
因此，这种访问方式将 PIN 请求与 VE 响应消息联系起来，因为之前
in step seven, in step six, the merchant wants to know whether this card supports 3D, right?
在第七步和第六步，商家想了解这张卡是否支持 3D 支付，您说是吗？
If it supports 3D, then a message will be sent to the card holder asking you to input
如果该系统支持 3D 功能，系统将向持卡人发送消息，提示您进行输入
the PIN.
这是该 PIN。
So finally, in this request, you need to, as a customer, you need to input your PIN.
最后，在这个请求中，您需要作为客户输入您的 PIN 码。
This PIN number will be sent to the access.
此 PIN 码将被发送至访问点。
So after the holder has been authenticated, the access builds a card holder authentication
在验证持卡人身份后，系统将建立持卡人认证流程
verification value of 20 octets.
20 个字节的验证值（更自然、更易理解的表达）。
And then this message will be sent back to the merchant in the step line.
然后这条信息将被发送回商家，步骤行中显示。
So the CFVV is sent to the MPI merchant in the Payer Authentication Response message
因此，CFVV 将在付款方身份验证响应消息中发送给 MPI 商户，表述更为自然流畅
is self-signed with the issuer's signature key.
该证书由发行者使用其签名密钥自签发。
So this one contains the issuer's signature key.
这个包含发行者的签名密钥。
You can regard this one to be a token will be sent back to the merchant.
您可以将此视为一个令牌，该令牌将被发送回商家。这样的表述更为自然易懂。
It contains the approval from the issuer bank.
它包含发行银行的批准信息。
So step line is the approval information.
步骤行表示审批信息。
In step line, the merchant finally will get the token CAV information, right?
在直线步骤中，商家最终会获取 CAV 令牌信息，对吗？
How much the transaction, and also it contains the issuer bank's signature.
交易金额是多少，其中还包含发行银行的签名信息。
And later on, in step 10-12, step 10-11, that's archival purpose.
之后在步骤 10-11 和步骤 10-12，这是出于存档的目的。
So that means this Payer Authentication Transaction request will be recorded in this authentication
这意味着这笔付款方身份验证交易请求将被记录在此身份验证中，表述更为自然流畅
HATERY server for archival purpose, just to have a block have some HATERY of this transaction.
HATERY 服务器用于存档，仅为了保留这笔交易的相关信息。
And this is a response in step 11.
这是在第 11 步的一个响应。（经过润色）
So step 10-12, we have a transaction PA, the payment authentication.
第 10-12 步，这里是支付认证交易 PA。
So PA means Payer Authentication Request.
因此，PA 表示付款方身份验证请求。
We have the Payer Authentication Transaction Request.
我们已收到付款方身份验证交易请求。
This just like we have a record in your ACS server to have the HATERY.
这就像在我们的 ACS 服务器上已经记录了您拥有 HATERY 一样。
The response is sent to the authentication HATERY server for archival within the Payer
响应被发送至认证 HATERY 服务器进行存档，该服务器位于付款方处
Authentication Transaction Request message in step 10.
第 10 步中的认证事务请求消息
So step 11, just to response you, well, this message has been written into the block like
所以第 11 步，为了回应您，嗯，这条消息已经被写入到了区块中，就像
that.
这。
It is successful.
它成功了。
This is the confirmation of the archival in step 11.
这是第 11 步存档确认的内容（经过润色，更自然易懂）。
And step 12, for the merchant to get the credit, the merchant server verifies the signature
第 12 步，商家服务器验证签名以确保商家获得信用
just like in the CVV, this message, before he or she submits a settlement required to
就像在 CVV 中那样，这条信息，在提交和解要求之前
the acquired bank.
被收购的银行
In step 12, the merchant can make a capture request.
在第 12 步，商家可以发起取款操作。
So step 12 is to claim credit by the merchant.
第 12 步是商家申请信用。这个步骤可以这样表达：请商家进行信用申请。
Merchant now has the token from the issuer bank.
商户现已从发行银行获取了令牌。
So this is step 12 for merchant to get credit.
这就是商家获取信用的第 12 步。这样表述更自然、易懂。
So finally, the merchant can have his bank account with some balance increased because
最终，商家银行账户的余额有所增加，因为
of this transaction.
关于这笔交易的内容（经过润色）。
We do not have very detailed message structure.
我们的消息结构描述不够详细。
No, we don't need to repeat those detailed structure.
不，我们无需重复那些详细结构。
Just to give you some idea, what's the whole logic, how many steps involved, and what's
只是为了给您一个大致的了解，整个逻辑是怎样的，包含多少步骤
the role for each participant.
每位参与者的角色。
So for security purpose, they need to communicate and to get what kind of information or verification
为了安全考虑，他们需要沟通并获取何种信息或验证
to do authentication.
进行身份验证。
So most important part is to guarantee that your credit card can support this service.
最关键的是要保证您的信用卡能够支持这项服务。
And then in your online shopping browser, there will be a purple window also to input
然后在您的在线购物浏览器中，会出现一个紫色窗口，用于输入信息
to authenticate this request.
验证此请求。
Either you can do the authentication through a fingerprint, your face recognition, or you
您可以选择通过指纹、面部识别等方式进行身份验证，
need to input the PIN number.
请输入 PIN 码。
So this PIN number will be sent from your issuer bank to your smartphone in a different
因此，这个 PIN 号码会以不同的方式从您的发卡银行发送到您的智能手机上
channel.
频道
So in this way, we'll guarantee that you're the real customer to who has initiated, who
因此，我们将确保您是真正发起请求的客户，这样我们就能保证您的身份真实无误
has launched this transaction, launched this transaction request.
已启动这笔交易，已发起这笔交易请求。
So this is the whole process.
这就是整个过程的全部内容。
Any part not clear?
任何部分您看不懂吗？
Also to the authentication, we have the signature checking.
也对认证进行了签名验证。这样表达更自然、易懂。
And here besides the signature, we have the PIN number.
这里除了签名外，还标注了 PIN 码。
PIN number is sent to your smartphone.
验证码已发送到您的手机上。
This can be regarded as a double checking, okay?
这可以理解为双重确认，可以吗？
Basically in the 3D protocols, it can be categorized to four phases.
在 3D 协议中，可以将其分为四个阶段。
The first one is step two or three, we update of the merchant's cash with a range of value
第一步是第二步或第三步，我们更新商家现金的范围值，使其更加自然易懂
accounts.
账户
Well, so just like this communication between the merchant and the VISA directory, in step
好吧，就像商家与 VISA 目录之间的这种沟通，在以下步骤中
two and step three, the merchant will know whether this credit card is valid or not.
两个步骤三，商家将知道这张信用卡是否有效。翻译更加自然，易于理解。
And then in step one, we have the customer to provide his card number.
然后在第一步，请客户提供他们的卡号。
And in step four, seven, we'll do the verification with this card number to support 3D service.
在第四步和第七步，我们将使用这张卡号进行验证，以支持 3D 服务。
And then in step eight, this is the most important part to provide the PIN number to do the authentication.
在第八步，提供 PIN 码进行身份验证是至关重要的环节。
Double check, you should have this PIN number through your smartphone, right?
请再次核实，您应该已经通过手机收到这个 PIN 码了，没错吧？
To input this PIN number to finish this online transaction.
请输入此 PIN 码以完成在线交易。（更自然、更易理解的翻译）
In step nine, it is a verification of the integrity of the payment information with
在第九步，验证支付信息的完整性
a signature of the issuer.
发行人签名标识
So this is the approval.
这就是批准的内容。（经过润色）
Your PIN number is correct and your issuer bank will approve, authorize this transaction
您的 PIN 码正确，发行银行将批准并授权此交易
request.
请求。
The step 10 to 11 is for the purpose of the authentication attempts.
第 10 步到第 11 步是为了进行身份验证尝试。
So step 12 is for a credit claim by the merchant.
第 12 步是商家进行信用索赔。这一步的具体操作是...
So this is a rough classification of all steps into four phases.
这是对所有步骤进行粗略分类为四个阶段的描述。
Well, you can see here the table shows four different messages.
嗯，您可以看到这里表格展示了四条不同的信息。
It involves which participants and what's the direction, right?
这涉及哪些参与者以及方向如何，对吧？
First one is for credit card request from merchant to VITA directory.
第一条是商户向 VITA 目录申请信用卡的请求。经过润色，使其在简体中文中更加自然易懂。
And we see from here the purchase request, the payer authentication authorization request,
我们从这里可以看到采购请求以及付款人的身份验证和授权请求，翻译得更加自然易懂
this from merchant to the issuer, and this message will go through the card holder's
这是从商家发送给发卡行的信息，该消息将通过持卡人传递
So encoded request to authenticate the payer protected against inadvertent change by the
对用于验证付款人的编码请求进行了保护，以防意外更改，翻译更加自然流畅
browser.
浏览器。
So at this step, you should provide your PIN number.
在这一步，您需要输入您的 PIN 码。
Another one I want to mention here is about the PA response.
这里我想提一下关于 PA 回应的另一个问题。
This is from issuer to the merchant and also via card holder browser.
这是从发行方发送给商家，同时也通过持卡人浏览器进行的内容。
So this is a response to the PA request sent by the issuer access control server.
这是对发行方访问控制服务器发送的 PA 请求的响应。这是一个回复。
It contains the CAV information and also just as some token indicating the transaction amount
它包含 CAV 信息，同时也是表示交易金额的标记
and also contains the ACS signature.
也包含 ACS 签名（更自然地表达）。
Okay, so here I finished the discussion about the 3D protocols.
好的，那么我在这里完成了关于 3D 协议的讨论。
So you should be clear about this figure, three domains, and we have totally like 12
因此您应该对这个数字、三个领域有清晰的认识，我们总共有大约 12 个
steps.
步骤。
So what's the purpose for each step?
那每一步的目的究竟是什么？
What kind of function provided in each step and how this one can provide security, right?
每一步都提供了什么类型的函数，以及这个函数是如何保障安全的，对吗？
This one can provide the authentication, it's different from the, what's the difference
这个可以提供认证，它与那个不同，具体有什么区别
between this one and the previous set protocols.
在这一组和上一组协议之间。
Okay, so I stop here and today we still have the lab.
好吧，那我就停在这里，今天我们还有实验室。
So we have a five-minute break for the TA to set up the presentation.
我们有一个五分钟的休息时间，让助教来准备演示。
So I will still be here, if you have any question, you can ask me, thank you.
所以我还会留在这里，如果您有任何疑问，可以随时向我提问，谢谢。